Davran Damkhan

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer

Future Data Scientist with advanced knowledge of Machine Learning, Image Processing, Computer Vision and Statistics. Have research experience in power engineering and Deep Learning. Detail-oriented, fast learning and creative skills with great abilities in teamwork.

davran.damkhan@nu.edu.kz

87075636734

Nur-Sultan, Kazakhstan

linkedin.com/in/Davran Damkhan

instagram.com/@davran.damkhan

Davran Damkhan

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Electrical and Computer Engineering

Nazarbayev University

08/2018 - Present

Nur-Sultan

Courses

Computer Science

Digital Image Processing

- Power Analysis

Microprocessors

Computer Networks

Machine Learning with Python

Probability and Statistics

- Computer Vision

- Complete Data Science Bootcamp (Udemy)

Foundation Year Program Nazarbayev University

09/2017 - 05/2018

Nur-Sultan

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Deep-learning-based approach for High Voltage Insulator inspection using UAV (09/2019 - Present)

 Inspection of HV insulator faults using UAV drones, image processing and deep learning algorithm (CNN)

Electric energy generator (03/2016 - 05/2017)

- Generating energy from walking using piezo-quarts elements

WORK EXPERIENCE

Robotics Engineer

Astana Business Campus Fab Lab

01/2019 - 06/2019 Nur-Sultan

- Designing Robot Hexapod using Arduino microcontroller and Android application

Sales Manager Company Al-Naz

07/2020 - 11/2020 Shymkent Responsible for leading and guiding a team of sales people in an organization

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

Bronze medal (2017)

International Project Competition, Almaty, Kazakhstan

Gold Medal (2016)

Regional Project Olympiad, Shymkent, Kazakhstan

Silver Medal (2017)

Young Inventors Project Competition, Astana, Kazakhstan

CERTIFICATES

IELTS (2017)

Cisco Certified Network Professional (2017)

LANGUAGES

Professional Working Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency Kazakh Turkish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency

SOFTWARES AND PROGRAMMING **LANGUAGES**

